<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
  <title>Dale Manning</title>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2013-07-29T13:02:14+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Dale Manning</name>
    <email>dalemmanning@gmail.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://locahost:4000/comics/2013/03/26/dark-victory</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://locahost:4000/comics/2013/03/26/dark-victory/"/>
    <title>Batman Reread 02 - Dark Victory</title>
    <updated>2013-03-26T13:05:48+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dale Manning</name>
      <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you read my first post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://dalemmanning.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/batman-reread-01-the-long-halloween/&quot; title=&quot;Batman Reread 01: The Long Halloween&quot;&gt;The Long Halloween&lt;/a&gt;, you will know that I've decided to reread the Batman graphic novels which I currently own. This week's post is about it's sequel Dark Victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Victory is made up of 13 issues, once again written by the original team behind The Long Halloween - Jeph Loeb and Tim Sale. Published in 1999 to 2000, the storyline once again takes place over the course of a year. With regards to continuity, it is set during Batman's third/fourth year of being the Dark Knight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central plot is very similar to The Long Halloween with Batman trying to stop a serial killer known as 'The Hangman', who is killing Gotham City police officers and once again the killings occur on holidays. With the sub-plot being the territory war between Two-Face and the Falcone family, lead by a wheelchair bound Sofia Falcone. As the story develops Batman becomes more of a loner, distancing himself from Gordon, Catwoman and even Alfred. The reason for this seems to be just how much he blames himself for what happened to Harvey Dent and how he refuses to allow it to happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;But … I was wrong about him being Holiday and … I can't afford to be wrong again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Alfred:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There's nothing wrong with being wrong, Sir. Even I'm not infallible on the occasion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Batman can't be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above quote stands out to me as one of the most important lines in the entire story. It signifies the start of what would become one of Batman's greatest strengths or weaknesses (depending on how you look at it). His sheer determination to make sure that in the future he only goes after the people who are guilty is ultimately one of the core building blocks of who Batman is today. However it's also the reason why he become such a loner, he feels that it is easier to prevent mistakes if the only person he has to trust is himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also see the persona of Bruce Wayne becoming much smaller here and by the end it is very much a case that Bruce Wayne is Batman's alter ego rather than vice versa, with his relationship with Selina Kyle becoming such a struggle that she eventually leaves him and moves away from Gotham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know with your considerable resources you could eventually find me, but please believe me -- I do not want to be found. Take care, Bruce. Alfred is right you are a very complicated man … - &lt;strong&gt;Selina Kyle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like The Long Halloween, Dark Victory is a murder mystery filled with plenty of twists. However I will be honest, as a standalone storyline it is weaker than its predecessor and in reality is very dependant on The Long Halloween. It does make me wonder how the readers felt in 1999 if they started picking up the issues having either read halloween two years previously or never having read it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final key point here is that Dark Victory also retells the origins of Robin, the sidekick who you either love or hate. A point which is raised by Tim Sale in his introduction to the book. I have to say the introduction of Dick Grayson is handled brilliantly. We get to see Batman struggling with being a father figure to the kid and realising the best way is to be completely honest with him. Throughout the later part of the story we get to see the relationship develop, as they hunt for the killers of  Dick's parents and which eventually sees him don the costume which is so contrasting with Batman's own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I can't change your mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dick:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;No way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You might want to rethink the yellow cape.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dick:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Nope. These were the colours my parents wore in the circus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;And what is it you want to call yourself?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Dick:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&quot;Robin&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Batman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Batman and Robin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short I did really enjoy rereading Dark Victory. Leob and Sale should be praised for what they attempted to do here, it can't have been a easy to try and recreate their earlier success. Yes it does have its weaknesses, however it does also manage to develop the background of the Dark Knight and successfully delivers further insight into the Batman which we get to read about today. My only piece of advice - if you are going to read this, do yourself a favour and make sure you read The Long Halloween first.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://locahost:4000/general/2012/10/29/welcome</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://locahost:4000/general/2012/10/29/welcome/"/>
    <title>Welcome</title>
    <updated>2012-10-29T15:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Dale Manning</name>
      <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi! Welcome to my blog which will primarily focus on Technology, Film and TV along with the occasional helping of Games, Comics and Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should explain why I've started the blog, well I want to try and write regularly for something other than work or study. I've always admired people who have the ability to post their thoughts online and after spending many, many hours each week reading blog posts on various sites I decided I wanted to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I will be honest this type of writing has never come easily to me, so please bear with me while I try and get used to things!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
 
</feed>